DANIELLE LINDBLOM

Portfolio: <u>DanielleLindblom.com</u>

LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedIncom/in/danielle-lindblom/

Missoula, Montana (218) - 205 - 4992

Danielle.Lindblom@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Resourceful and considerate engineering professional with 10+ years of experience solving complex problems and improving processes in diverse contexts. Ready to aid your company in producing organized and user-friendly frontend web development solutions. Specialties include: React, JavaScript, web accessibility and inclusive design, continuous process improvement, and technical training and documentation.

SKILLS

- Frontend Web Development: React, JavaScript, HTML & CSS, Git & GitHub, VSCode, Bootstrap, Sass, Accessibility, Pairs Programming, Group Projects
- **Professional:** Continuous Improvement & Kaizen, Technical Training & Documentation, Team Leadership, Project Management, Coaching & Mentoring

PROJECTS

Codedex Hackathon 2024

Worked collaboratively with 2 randomly chosen teammates to create a working, animated single page website in 24 hours utilizing React, CSS, and GitHub

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota Minneapolis

Bachelor of Science Mechanical Engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Implementation Specialist

Submittable | Feb 2022 - June 2024

- Designed a multi-stage custom automation workflow for customer IFF that utilized the Submittable API to reduce manual staff hours by 50% resulting in improved grant management
- Built and deployed the multi-lingual intake form for the State of Minnesota's Tax Rebate Program in under 1 week while emphasizing accessibility, resulting in smooth data collection, no interference with custom automations, and the distribution of \$1B to Minnesota citizens
- Identified, tested, and reported bugs in live production leading to more accurate reporting of issues, reduced customer frustration, and increased customer retention

Continuous Improvement Specialist

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Minnesota | Aug 2019 - Feb 2020 Pentair | April 2015 - March 2017 Collins Aerospace | July 2013 - July 2015

- Planned, coordinated, and executed a 12-month Lean
 Transformation project at Pentair for the 2-shift, 100 employee
 Cooling Assembly Area by leading cross-functional teams
 through several week-long kaizen process improvement events
 resulting in \$650k annual cost savings, 25% faster time to
 manufacture, and greatly improved employee morale
- Achieved Lean Practitioner Certification 2014

Small Business Owner

Danielle Lindblom Coaching | Oct 2018 - Feb 2022 High Spirits Dog Training | July 2014 - Aug 2019

- Built and updated websites for both businesses using Wix.com
- Managed all Business to Customer sales
- Specialized in Behavior Science and Change Management